<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
 <channel>
  <image>
   <url>
    https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/0/0/up-logo.jpg
   </url>
   <title>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua
   </link>
  </image>
  <title>
   Ukrainska Pravda
  </title>
  <link>
   https://www.pravda.com.ua
  </link>
  <description/>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russians attack Zaporizhzhia Oblast, one civil infrastructure facility on fire, civilian injured
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383483/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="77652" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/9/e/9ea6ab7-8840c88-63545bf-gettyimages-1237411394.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 23:44:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    On the evening of 3 January, the Russian invaders struck the outskirts of Zaporizhzhia with missiles. One person was injured as a result of the attack, and a fire broke out at a civilian infrastructure facility.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383483/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Explosions heard in Rostov and Kursk
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383481/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="106090" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/a/9/a928e8a-------.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 23:14:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    On 3 January, residents and eyewitnesses reported the sounds of explosions in the Russian cities of Rostov-on-Don and Kursk. 
Source: Radio Liberty Russia, videos from local Russian Telegram channels 
Details: In particular, residents are publishing photos and videos showing explosions in Russian cities.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383481/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Zelenskyy on destruction of Alta&amp;#239;r in Druzhkivka: This is another confession of the terrorist state
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383479/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="183907" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/4/f/4f9b449----.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:48:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    President Volodymyr Zelenskyy reacted to the destruction of the Alta&amp;iuml;r ice arena in Druzhkivka, Donetsk Oblast by the Russian occupiers; the arena was used for the collection and distribution of humanitarian aid.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383479/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Zelenskyy: Russia’s attempted offensive must become its final failure
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383478/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="149118" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/4/e/4e2c079-------.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:27:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Volodymyr Zelenskyy, the President of Ukraine, believes that the Russian government will deploy all Russian forces in order to try to change the outcome of the war and postpone their defeat. 
Source: Zelenskyy's video address on 3 January 
Quote: "We started this year with what Ukraine needs most right now - on the eve of new mobilisation processes being prepared by the terrorist state.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383478/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    AEW&amp;C aircraft that helps in targeting arrived in Belarus from Russia
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383477/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="143174" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/8/a/8a2685e---.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 22:17:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    An Il-76 A-50U aircraft, designed to track air and surface targets, arrived at the Machulishchy airfield in Belarus from Russia. 
Source: Belaruski Hajun [an independent Belarusian military monitoring media outlet] 
Quote: "At 21:25, an Il-76 A-50U AEW&amp;amp;C [airborne early warning and control - ed.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383477/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Ukraine Palace of Arts shares video of Russian rocket strike that damaged building
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383472/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="141600" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/8/d/8dd91b7-2.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 21:19:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    The Ukraine National Palace of Arts, a theatre, concert hall and official event venue, has posted a video filmed by surveillance cameras during a missile strike on the centre of Kyiv on 31 December which damaged the building.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383472/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Erdo&amp;#287;an to speak to Putin and Zelenskyy on Wednesday
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383471/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 21:15:08 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Turkish President Recep Tayyip Erdo&amp;#287;an plans to hold telephone conversations with his Ukrainian and Russian counterparts, Volodymyr Zelenskyy and Vladimir Putin, on Wednesday. 
This was announced on the NTV channel on Tuesday by Ibrahim Kalin, the advisor to the Turkish president, European Pravda reports.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383471/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russian medics flee from occupied Melitopol
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383468/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="145109" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/d/b/db8b607-68b388c-melitopol.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:31:41 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Russian medics are following in the wake of the collaborators and fleeing from the occupied city of Melitopol in Zaporizhzhia Oblast. 
Source: Ivan Fedorov, the mayor of Melitopol, on Telegram 
Quote: "The Melitopol city hospital was practically the last hospital in temporarily occupied Zaporizhzhia Oblast that was still providing medical care to civilians, but it has now been almost a month since the occupiers started bringing wounded and sick soldiers there, and there is less and less space for civilians in the hospital.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383468/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russian invader repeats rumours about full mobilisation in Russia in new intercepted call
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383467/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="194512" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/8/e/8ed3918-a7d9c10-gettyimages-1240933345--1-.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 20:27:04 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    In a phone call that was recently recorded by Defence Intelligence of the Ministry of Defence of Ukraine, a Russian soldier says there are rumours of a full mobilisation in Russia and describes the Russian command instructing troops to "attack" with minimal forces.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383467/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Zelenskyy thanked Norway's Prime Minister for energy support of Ukraine
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.eurointegration.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7153532/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:50:48 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description/>
   <guid>
    https://www.eurointegration.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7153532/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russians marching over corpses: Ukrainian Army Commander-in-Chief reports on situation at front
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383461/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="147769" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/5/1/510d94b-fd13569-0a59c1e-690.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:31:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Valerii Zaluzhnyi, the Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces of Ukraine, spoke with Mark Milley, the chairman of the US Joint Chiefs of Staff, on the phone for the first time this year on 3 January 2023, and reported on the situation at the front.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383461/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Half a million Ukrainian school-age children are currently living abroad
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383459/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:21:25 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    As of the beginning of January 2023, there are about 500,000 Ukrainian children of school age living abroad. At the beginning of the academic year [1 September - ed.], there were 488,000. 
This was announced by Serhii Shkarlet, the Minister of Education and Science of Ukraine, on the 24/7 national newscast.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383459/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Metal detectors and scanners in public spaces, Cabinet of Ministers plans to strengthen security in Ukraine
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383457/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="61475" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/3/4/3459ae4-thumb-198475-820-360-0-0-auto.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 19:06:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Prime Minister Denys Shmyhal has announced that metal detectors and scanners will be installed in public spaces for enhanced security of the citizens. 
Source: Shmyhal at a governmental meeting 
Quote: "In 2023, we will be actively forging the security infrastructure in our country.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383457/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Ukrainian forces hit two Russian command posts, occupiers attack near Bakhmut – General Staff report
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383453/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="436210" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/f/e/fed6b60-opera--------2023-01-03-182906-scontent-iev1-1.xx.fbcdn.net.png"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 18:22:27 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Over the past 24 hours, units of the Armed Forces of Ukraine hit two command posts of Russians; the invaders did not quit attempting to reach the administrative border of Donetsk Oblast and tried to conduct offensive operations on the Bakhmut front 
Source: General Staff of the Armed Forces of Ukraine 
Details: Aviation of  Ukraine's defence forces carried out four strikes on clusters of Russian military personnel, weapons and equipment.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383453/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Kreminna-Svatove highway under fire control of Armed Forces of Ukraine
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383450/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="62239" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/d/7/d7249f0-------.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 18:08:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Serhiy Haidai, the head of Luhansk Oblast, has said that the Kreminna-Svatove highway is under the fire control of the Ukrainian Defenders and now the logistics of the Russian invaders have become much more complicated.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383450/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Zelenskyy discussed defenсe cooperation with UK Prime Minister
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.eurointegration.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7153525/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 17:54:36 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description/>
   <guid>
    https://www.eurointegration.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7153525/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russians hit trolleybus in Kherson
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383443/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="332755" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/d/c/dccdb8e-opera--------2023-01-03-173700-miskrada.kherson.ua.png"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 17:35:18 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Russian soldiers have attacked Khersonelectrotrans, a state-owned regional utility company, in the city of Kherson, hitting one of trolleybuses and an administrative building.  
Source: press service of Kherson City State Council quoting Halyna Luhova, Head of Kherson City Military Administration 
Details: A projectile hit one of trolleybuses.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383443/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russia keeps nuclear weapons carriers in Crimea
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383442/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="83254" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/6/c/6cb4c22-7755486-krym.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 17:34:00 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    The Defence Intelligence of Ukraine has said that Russia keeps its ground-based, air-launched and sea-based carriers of nuclear weapons in temporarily occupied Crimea.  
Source: Ukrinform news agency, quoting Andrii Cherniak, representative of the Defence Intelligence 
Quote: "The Defence Intelligence sees that carriers of nuclear weapons that are ground-based, air-launched and sea-based are located in the territory of temporarily occupied Crimea at the moment.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383442/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Ukrainian Air Force explains why they don’t shoot down Shahed UAVs flying along Dnipro
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383431/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="59364" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/3/2/32cf917-ad19440-c3355fb-0d5af15-49-main-v1666599214.jpg"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 15:35:27 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    The Russian forces most often launch Iranian-made kamikaze drones at night along the Dnipro riverbed, because this way, it is harder to detect the UAVs with radar. 
Source: Yurii Ihnat, spokesman for the Ukrainian Air Force, on the air of Ukrainian Radio 
Details: When asked why the air defence does not shoot down UAVs moving along the Dnipro River, the Air Force spokesman noted: 
Quote: "Because they become less visible on radar the closer they press to the ground.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383431/
   </guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Russian forces blow up power plant during retreat from Beryslav, Kherson Oblast
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383430/
   </link>
   <category>
    News
   </category>
   <dc:creator>
    Ukrainska Pravda
   </dc:creator>
   <enclosure length="598318" type="image/jpeg" url="https://img.pravda.com/images/doc/f/1/f180a78-opera--------2023-01-03-153338-deepstatemap.live.png"/>
   <pubDate>
    Tue, 03 Jan 2023 15:28:03 +0200
   </pubDate>
   <description>
    Russian troops have blown up a power plant during their retreat from Beryslav, Kherson Oblast, in November. 
Source: Oleksii Reznikov, Ukrainian Minister of Defence, on Twitter 
Quote: "In Beryslav (Kherson region), Russians retreated and intentionally blew up a power plant.
   </description>
   <guid>
    https://www.pravda.com.ua/eng/news/2023/01/3/7383430/
   </guid>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>